<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?> 
<!-- Generated by Fujitsu XWand B0064 -->
<linkbase xmlns="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/linkbase" xmlns:xbrli="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:gri-core="http://www.grig3.org/XBRL/2006/">
<label xlink:type="resource" xlink:label="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_terseLabel" xlink:role="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/role/terseLabel" xml:lang="en" id="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_terseLabel">EN22</label>
    <label xlink:type="resource" xlink:label="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_label" xlink:role="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/role/label" xml:lang="en" id="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_label">EN22</label>
    <label xlink:type="resource" xlink:label="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_guidelineDefinition" xlink:role="http://www.globalreporting.org/2006/G3/guidelineDefinition" xml:lang="en" id="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_guidelineDefinition">Total weight of waste by type and disposal method. (Core)</label>
    <label xlink:type="resource" xlink:label="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_protocolRelevance" xlink:role="http://www.globalreporting.org/2006/G3/protocolRelevance" xml:lang="en" id="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_protocolRelevance">Data on waste generation figures over several years can indicate the level of progress the organization has made toward waste reduction efforts. It can also indicate potential improvements in process efficiency and productivity. From a financial perspective, the reduction of waste contributes directly to lower costs for materials, processing, and disposal.   Information about the disposal destination reveals the extent to which a reporting organization has managed the balance between disposal options and uneven environmental impacts. For example, land filling and recycling create very different types of environmental impacts and residual effects. Most waste minimization strategies emphasize prioritizing options for recovery, reuse, or recycling over other disposal options, wherever possible. </label>
    <label xlink:type="resource" xlink:label="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_protocolCompilation" xlink:role="http://www.globalreporting.org/2006/G3/protocolCompilation" xml:lang="en" id="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_protocolCompilation">2.1 Identify the amount of waste created by the organization&#8217;s operations, by:  - Hazardous waste (as defined by national legislation at the point of generation); and  - Non-hazardous waste (all other forms of solid or liquid waste excluding wastewater).   2.2 If no weight data are available, estimate the weight using available information on waste density and volume collected, mass balances, or similar information.   2.3 Report the total amount of waste in tonnes by type as identified in 2.1 for each of the following disposal methods:  - Composting;  - Reuse;  - Recycling;  - Recovery;  - Incineration (or use as fuel);  - Landfill;  - Deep well injection;  - On-site storage; and  - Other (to be specified by the reporting organization).   2.4 Report how the method of disposal has been determined:  - Disposed directly by the reporting organization or otherwise directly confirmed;  - Information provided by the waste disposal contractor; or  - Organizational defaults of the waste disposal contractor. </label>
    <label xlink:type="resource" xlink:label="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_protocolDocumentation" xlink:role="http://www.globalreporting.org/2006/G3/protocolDocumentation" xml:lang="en" id="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_protocolDocumentation">Potential information sources include external waste audits by providers of disposal services or waste balance sheets from these providers, as well as internal billing and accounting systems, and the procurement or supply management department. </label>
    <label xlink:type="resource" xlink:label="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_protocolDefinition" xlink:role="http://www.globalreporting.org/2006/G3/protocolDefinition" xml:lang="en" id="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_protocolDefinition">Disposal method. The method by which waste is treated or disposed, including composting, reuse, recycling, recovery, incineration, landfill, deep well injection, and on-site storage.</label>
    <label xlink:type="resource" xlink:label="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_protocolReference" xlink:role="http://www.globalreporting.org/2006/G3/protocolReference" xml:lang="en" id="gri-core_EN22_lbl_en_protocolReference">Ban Amendment to the Basel Convention on the Control of Transboundary Movements of Hazardous Wastes and their Disposal, 1989. ? London Dumping Convention, 1972. ? MARPOL Convention (International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution of Ships), 1973.</label>
</linkbase>
